<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Compliance on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</title>
    <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/compliance.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Compliance on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 15:50:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/compliance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Governance and guardrails for researchers with RONIN ISOLATE</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/governance-and-guardrails-for-researchers-with-ronin-isolate.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 15:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/governance-and-guardrails-for-researchers-with-ronin-isolate.html</guid>
      <description>RONIN (www.ronin.cloud) is one of our favorite HPC partners, because they&amp;rsquo;ve done a really comprehensive job providing research customers the governance and guardrails they need around budget management and data security to make insanely easy to explore and experiment with workloads in the cloud. It helps that they pack hundreds of DevOps tasks into every click so you can launch HPC clusters in less time than it takes to buy your groceries online.
Tara Madhyastha is one of RONIN&amp;rsquo;s Principal Research Scientists based out of Seattle, and she gives us a peek at a new product built on RONIN Core called &amp;lsquo;RONIN Isolate&amp;rsquo;, which takes secure enclaves and project isolation to an obsessive new level to help customers with really extreme (and particular) security and compliance needs.
Isolate launched this week, and you can find more about it at the RONIN Blo at https://blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating research and development of new medical treatments with HPC on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/accelerating-research-and-development-of-new-medical-treatments-with-hpc-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/accelerating-research-and-development-of-new-medical-treatments-with-hpc-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>Today, more than 290,000 researchers in France are working to provide better support and care for patients through modern medical treatment. To fulfill their mission, these researchers must be equipped with powerful tools. At AWS, we believe that technology has a critical role to play in medical research. Why? Because technology can take advantage of the significant amount of data generated in the healthcare system and in the research community to enable opportunities for more accurate diagnoses, and better treatments for many existing and future diseases. To support elite research in France, we are proud to be a sponsor of two French organizations: Gustave Roussy and Sorbonne University. AWS is providing them with the computing power and machine learning technologies needed to accelerate cancer research and develop a treatment for COVID-19.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
