<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>research on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</title>
    <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/research.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in research on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 15:00:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A new GUI for building and managing clusters - PCluster Manager</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/a-new-gui-for-building-and-managing-clusters-pcluster-manager.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 15:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/a-new-gui-for-building-and-managing-clusters-pcluster-manager.html</guid>
      <description>Charlie Gruenweld, our newest Principal Engineer in the HPC org, took advantage of the new API in ParallelCluster and a few dozen years of web development revolutions to build a snappy UI for creating and managing clusters that makes it nearly impossible to go wrong - and gives you immediate access to some of ParallelCluster&amp;rsquo;s most powerful features.
In less than 20 minutes, you&amp;rsquo;ll grok how to create a cluster, run jobs, spawn elastic (disposable) nodes, and jump into a full graphical desktop to run visual applications on the cluster itself.
This is the project that brings it all together. I hope you enjoy this as much as I did.
If you have ideas for technical topics you&amp;rsquo;d like to see us cover in a future show, let us know by finding us on Twitter (@TechHpc) and DM&amp;rsquo;ing us with your idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Chemistry Calculation with FHI-aims code on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/quantum-chemistry-calculation-with-fhi-aims-code-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/quantum-chemistry-calculation-with-fhi-aims-code-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>This article was contributed by Dr. Fabio Baruffa, Sr. HPC and QC Solutions Architect at AWS, and Dr. Jesús Pérez Ríos, Group Leader at the Fritz Haber Institute, Max-Planck Society. Introduction Quantum chemistry – the study of the inherently quantum interactions between atoms forming part of molecules – is a cornerstone of modern chemistry. […]
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for participation: PRACE Winter School</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/call-for-participation-prace-winter-school.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/call-for-participation-prace-winter-school.html</guid>
      <description>The Inter University Computing Centre (IUCC) in Israel and AWS have joined forces to train Researchers and Research Software Engineers (RSEs) in the use of AWS for High Performance Computing (HPC) at the PRACE Winter School, 7-9 December 2021, and we’re calling for interested groups to sign up and join us.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting climate model simulations to accelerate climate science</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/supporting-climate-model-simulations-to-accelerate-climate-science.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/supporting-climate-model-simulations-to-accelerate-climate-science.html</guid>
      <description>The Amazon Sustainability Data Initiative (ASDI), AWS is donating cloud resources, technical support, and access to scalable infrastructure and fast networking providing high performance computing solutions to support simulations of near-term climate using the National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR) Community Earth System Model Version 2 (CESM2) and its Whole Atmosphere Community Climate Model (WACCM). In collaboration with ASDI, AWS, and SilverLining, a nonprofit dedicated to ensuring a safe climate, the National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR) will run an ensemble of 30 climate-model simulations on AWS. The climate runs will simulate the Earth system over the period of years 2022-2070 under a median scenario for warming and make them available through the AWS Open Data Program. The simulation work will demonstrate the ability to use cloud infrastructure to advance climate models in support of robust scientific studies by researchers around the world and aims to accelerate and democratize climate science.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
