<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>docker on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</title>
    <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/docker.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in docker on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 16:48:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Containers, Episode II - the Runtimes Strike Back</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/containers-episode-ii-the-runtimes-strike-back.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 16:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/containers-episode-ii-the-runtimes-strike-back.html</guid>
      <description>Christian Kniep (our senior developer relations engineer) from HPC Engineering is back to finish the conversation we started about containers in HPC. Christian is leading the cause for containerization in HPC, and helping our engineering and product teams focus on enabling that path on AWS.
Today we&amp;rsquo;re talking about how containers work in a shared infrastructure environment, with shared filesystems (like Lustre) and we&amp;rsquo;ll also cover multi-node parallelism, too, since MPI is where it&amp;rsquo;s at for many (most?) people in the HPC community.
(And we completely missed thew opportunity to make any April fools jokes, so everything we say is totally believable) :-)
If you have ideas for technical topics you&amp;rsquo;d like to see us cover in a future show, let us know by finding us on Twitter (@TechHpc) and DM&amp;rsquo;ing us with your idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Containers in HPC - what they fix and what they break (and how to fix that, too)</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/containers-in-hpc-what-they-fix-and-what-they-break-and-how-to-fix-that-too.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 16:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/containers-in-hpc-what-they-fix-and-what-they-break-and-how-to-fix-that-too.html</guid>
      <description>Today we&amp;rsquo;re joined by Christian Kniep who is one of our senior developer advocates in HPC Engineering. Christian is leading the cause for containerization in HPC, and helping our engineering and product teams focus on enabling that path on AWS.
We know containers are a &amp;lsquo;mixed&amp;rsquo; topic for HPC folks, and so we&amp;rsquo;re starting a series of Tech Shorts to talk about what they are, what problems they solve, what new problems they create, and what solutions exist to address those.
Today is part 1, where we talk about how containers work generally, how they work on AWS, with things like AWS Nitro and GPUs in play.
Next week, we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about containers in shared infrastructure and multi-node parallelism, too.
The FOSDEM devroom we spoke about is here: https://tinyurl.com/fosdemhpc21 and you can find Christian on twitter here https://twitter.com/CQnib - pick up the conversation with him if you have some thoughts about containers and how they work for you (or not).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
