<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>financial-services on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</title>
    <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/financial-services.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in financial-services on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/financial-services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Financial Services on AWS HPC</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/financial-services.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/financial-services.html</guid>
      <description> Learn about Financial Services on AWS HPC </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A serverless architecture for high performance financial modelling</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/a-serverless-architecture-for-high-performance-financial-modelling.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/a-serverless-architecture-for-high-performance-financial-modelling.html</guid>
      <description>Understanding deal and portfolio risk and capital requirements is a computationally expensive process that requires the execution of multiple financial forecasting models every day and in often in real time. This post describes how it works at RenaissanceRe, one of the world’s leading reinsurance companies.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud-native, high throughput grid computing using the AWS HTC-Grid solution</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/cloud-native-high-throughput-grid-computing-using-the-aws-htc-grid-solution.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/cloud-native-high-throughput-grid-computing-using-the-aws-htc-grid-solution.html</guid>
      <description>We worked with our financial services customers to develop an open-source, scalable, cloud-native, high throughput computing solution on AWS — AWS HTC-Grid. HTC-Grid allows you to submit large volumes of short and long running tasks and scale environments dynamically. In this first blog of a two-part series, we describe the structure of HTC-Grid and its objective to provide a configurable blueprint for HPC grid scheduling on the cloud.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling a read-intensive, low-latency file system to 10M&#43; IOPs</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/scaling-a-read-intensive-low-latency-file-system-to-10m-iops.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/scaling-a-read-intensive-low-latency-file-system-to-10m-iops.html</guid>
      <description>Many shared file systems are used in supporting read-intensive applications, like financial backtesting. These applications typically exploit copies of datasets whose authoritative copy resides somewhere else. For small datasets, in-memory databases and caching techniques can yield impressive results. However, low latency flash-based scalable shared file systems can provide both massive IOPs and bandwidth. They’re also easy to adopt because of their use of a file-level abstraction. In this post, I’ll share how to easily create and scale a shared, distributed POSIX compatible file system that performs at local NVMe speeds for files opened read-only.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Convergent Evolution of Grid Computing in Financial Services</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/the-convergent-evolution-of-grid-computing-in-financial-services.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/the-convergent-evolution-of-grid-computing-in-financial-services.html</guid>
      <description>The Financial Services industry makes significant use of high performance computing (HPC) but it tends to be in the form of loosely coupled, embarrassingly parallel workloads to support risk modelling. The infrastructure tends to scale out to meet ever increasing demand as the analyses look at more and finer grained data. At AWS we’ve helped many customers tackle scaling challenges are noticing some common themes. In this post we describe how HPC teams are thinking about how they deliver compute capacity today, and highlight how we see the solutions converging for the future.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HPC in Financial Services is not boring, and has some interesting problems to solve.</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/hpc-in-financial-services-is-not-boring-and-has-some-interesting-problems-to-solve.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 15:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/hpc-in-financial-services-is-not-boring-and-has-some-interesting-problems-to-solve.html</guid>
      <description>HPC in Financial Services is interesting for a lot of reasons that have nothing to do with banking. It&amp;rsquo;s an embarrassingly parallel workload, typically made up from zillions of short&amp;rsquo;ish jobs (seconds to minutes). And the decisions it supports are pretty big ones: whole banks and entire economies might be impacted by the outcomes. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting because there are so many fun ways you can solve the problem of &amp;lsquo;get it done fast, cheaply, and soon enough to help the people who are making really big decisions&amp;rsquo;. And whilst you expect us to say this: the cloud truly is a real game changer for this workload.
Alex Kimber wrote the HPC book at AWS for Financial Services, but what he talks about in this short discussion puts context around the whole thing &amp;hellip; He&amp;rsquo;ll be back to expand on several of the key points in a few weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable and Cost-Effective Batch Processing for ML workloads with AWS Batch and Amazon FSx</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/scalable-and-cost-effective-batch-processing-for-ml-workloads-with-aws-batch-and-amazon-fsx.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/scalable-and-cost-effective-batch-processing-for-ml-workloads-with-aws-batch-and-amazon-fsx.html</guid>
      <description>Batch processing is a common need across varied machine learning use cases such as video production, financial modeling, drug discovery, or genomic research. The elasticity of the cloud provides efficient ways to scale and simplify batch processing workloads while cutting costs. In this post, you’ll learn a scalable and cost-effective approach to configure AWS Batch Array jobs to process datasets that are stored on Amazon S3 and presented to compute instances with Amazon FSx for Lustre.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
