<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</title>
    <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/author.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/author/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Angel Pizarro</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/author/angel-pizarro.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/author/angel-pizarro.html</guid>
      <description>Angel is a Principal Developer Advocate for HPC and scientific computing. His background is in bioinformatics application development and building system architectures for scalable computing in genomics and other high throughput life science domains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brendan Bouffler</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/author/brendan-bouffler.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/author/brendan-bouffler.html</guid>
      <description>Boof (Brendan Bouffler) is the head of our Developer Relations group in HPC Engineering at AWS.
He’s been guilty of responsible for designing and building hundreds of HPC systems in all kind of environments, all over the world. However, he joined AWS when it became clear to him that cloud would become the exceptional tool the global research &amp;amp; engineering community needed to bring on the discoveries that would change the world for us all.
He holds a degree in Physics and an interest in testing several of its laws as they apply to bicycles.
This has, unfortunately, frequently resulted in hospitalization.
You can find him on twitter at @boofla, and on linkedIn, or hanging out somewhere with Elmo, who often appears in HPC Tech Shorts</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matt Vaughn</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/author/matt-vaughn.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/author/matt-vaughn.html</guid>
      <description>Matt is a Principal Developer Advocate for HPC and scientific computing. He has a background in life sciences and building user-friendly HPC and cloud systems for long-tail users. When not in front of his laptop, he’s drawing, reading, travelling the world, or playing with the nearest dog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
