<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Climate/Environment/Weather on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</title>
    <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/categories/climate/environment/weather.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Climate/Environment/Weather on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/categories/climate/environment/weather/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting the Best Price Performance for Numerical Weather Prediction Workloads on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/getting-the-best-price-performance-for-numerical-weather-prediction-workloads-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/getting-the-best-price-performance-for-numerical-weather-prediction-workloads-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>In this post, we will provide an overview of Numerical Weather Prediction (NWP) workloads, and the AWS HPC-optimized services for it. We’ll test three popular NWP codes: WRF, MPAS, and FV3GFS.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Arm a world-leading forecast model with AWS Graviton and Lambda</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/how-to-arm-a-world-leading-forecast-model-with-aws-graviton-and-lambda.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/how-to-arm-a-world-leading-forecast-model-with-aws-graviton-and-lambda.html</guid>
      <description>The Met Office is the UK’s National Meteorological Service, providing 24×7 world-renowned scientific excellence in weather, climate and environmental forecasts and severe weather warnings for the protection of life and property. They provide forecasts and guidance for the public, to our government and defence colleagues as well as the private sector. As an example, if you’ve been on a plane over Europe, Middle East, or Africa; that plane took off because the Met Office (as one of two World Aviation Forecast Centres) provided a forecast. This article explains one of the ways they use AWS to collect these observations, which has freed them to focus more on top quality delivery for their customers.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running the Harmonie numerical weather prediction model on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-the-harmonie-numerical-weather-prediction-model-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-the-harmonie-numerical-weather-prediction-model-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>The Danish Meteorological Institute (DMI) is responsible for running atmospheric, climate and ocean models covering the kingdom of Denmark. We worked together with the DMI to port and run a full numerical weather prediction (NWP) cycling dataflow with the Harmonie Numerical Weather Prediction (NWP) model to AWS. You can find a report of the porting and operational experience in the ACCORD community newsletter. In this blog post, we expand on that report to present the initial timing results from running the forecast component of Harmonie model on AWS. We also present these as-is timing results together with as-is timings attained on the supercomputing systems based on Cray XC40 and Intel Xeon based Cray XC50.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting climate model simulations to accelerate climate science</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/supporting-climate-model-simulations-to-accelerate-climate-science.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/supporting-climate-model-simulations-to-accelerate-climate-science.html</guid>
      <description>The Amazon Sustainability Data Initiative (ASDI), AWS is donating cloud resources, technical support, and access to scalable infrastructure and fast networking providing high performance computing solutions to support simulations of near-term climate using the National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR) Community Earth System Model Version 2 (CESM2) and its Whole Atmosphere Community Climate Model (WACCM). In collaboration with ASDI, AWS, and SilverLining, a nonprofit dedicated to ensuring a safe climate, the National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR) will run an ensemble of 30 climate-model simulations on AWS. The climate runs will simulate the Earth system over the period of years 2022-2070 under a median scenario for warming and make them available through the AWS Open Data Program. The simulation work will demonstrate the ability to use cloud infrastructure to advance climate models in support of robust scientific studies by researchers around the world and aims to accelerate and democratize climate science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WRF performance teardown on Graviton vs x86</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/wrf-performance-teardown-on-graviton-vs-x86.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 16:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/wrf-performance-teardown-on-graviton-vs-x86.html</guid>
      <description>(A complete teardown of WRF performance on x86 and AWS Graviton, from memory subsystems, compilers and MPI stacks).
Weather simulation is a reliably difficult workload for almost any HPC architecture and is often used as a litmus test by many customers before they look too hard at a novel or different systems. Customers have asked us frequently about our performance for codes like WRF, and that’s been even more the case since we launched our Arm-based processor, the AWS Graviton2, in a range of EC2 instances.
So it’s exciting that Karthik Raman and Matt Koop (two leading engineers from our global HPC solution architecture team) dived deep to look at WRF’s performance across a range of instance types (both Intel and Graviton), with EFA (our fast fabric, as you might remember from last week) as well as investigating the impact of different MPIs and compilers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training forecasters to warn severe hazardous weather on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/training-forecasters-to-warn-severe-hazardous-weather-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/training-forecasters-to-warn-severe-hazardous-weather-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>Training users on how to use high performance computing resources — and the data that comes out as a result of those analyses — is an essential function of most research organizations. Having a robust, scalable, and easy-to-use platform for on-site and remote training is becoming a requirement for creating a community around your research mission. A great example of this comes from the NOAA National Weather Service Warning Decision Training Division (WDTD), which develops and delivers training on the integrated elements of the hazardous weather warning process within a National Weather Service (NWS) forecast office. In collaboration with the University of Oklahoma’s Cooperative Institute for Mesoscale Meteorological Studies (OU/CIMMS), WDTD conducts its flagship course, the Radar and Applications Course (RAC), for forecasters issuing warnings for flash floods, severe thunderstorms, and tornadoes. Trainees learn the warning process, the science and application of conceptual models, and technical aspects of analyzing radar and other weather data in the Advanced Weather Interactive Processing System (AWIPS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical weather prediction on AWS Graviton2</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/numerical-weather-prediction-on-aws-graviton2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/numerical-weather-prediction-on-aws-graviton2.html</guid>
      <description>The Weather Research and Forecasting (WRF) model is a numerical weather prediction (NWP) system designed to serve both atmospheric research and operational forecasting needs. With the release of Arm-based AWS Graviton2 Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2) instances, a common question has been how these instances perform on large-scale NWP workloads. In this blog, we will present results from a standard WRF benchmark simulation and compare across three different instance types.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
