<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pcluster manager on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</title>
    <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/pcluster-manager.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in pcluster manager on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 17:09:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/pcluster-manager/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Clusters in the Cloud made easier with PCluster Manager (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/clusters-in-the-cloud-made-easier-with-pcluster-manager-part-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 17:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/clusters-in-the-cloud-made-easier-with-pcluster-manager-part-2.html</guid>
      <description>In part 1, we covered all the aspects of designing and creating ParallelClusters in PCluster Manager. Today we delve into some more advanced topics like debugging your stack when something goes wrong, managing access to the cluster via the UI and CLI, and visualization, which is something that&amp;rsquo;s just super hard to do anywhere else.
Sean Smith shows us how this is all a lot easier with the right tools. if you want to install PCluster Manager in your account, head over to hpc.news/pclustermanager and deploy one of the one-click lauchable stacks to get going. There&amp;rsquo;s even an episode with Charlie (from our engineering team) showing how to install it and get it set up (it&amp;rsquo;s here: https://youtu.be/Z1vlpJYb1KQ).
If you have ideas for technical topics you&amp;rsquo;d like to see us cover in a future show, let us know by finding us on Twitter (@TechHpc) and DM&amp;rsquo;ing us with your idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clusters in the Cloud made easier with PCluster Manager (Part 1 of 2)</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/clusters-in-the-cloud-made-easier-with-pcluster-manager-part-1-of-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 16:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/clusters-in-the-cloud-made-easier-with-pcluster-manager-part-1-of-2.html</guid>
      <description>Today is the first part of a 2-part series and we&amp;rsquo;re covering all the aspects of designing and creating ParallelClusters using PCluster Manager, which is a graphical user interface tool for making all the hard bits of cluster management way less messy and so much easier. All the documentation in the world isn&amp;rsquo;t as useful as this one tool.
In part 2, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into some advanced topics like debugging your cluster build when something goes wrong, and we&amp;rsquo;ll show you some fancy access methods, and tools for managing jobs - and visualizing the results.
Sean Smith shows us how this is all a lot easier with the right tools. if you want to install PCluster Manager in your account, head over to hpc.news/pclustermanager and deploy one of the one-click lauchable stacks to get going. There&amp;rsquo;s even an episode with Charlie (from our engineering team) showing how to install it and get it set up (it&amp;rsquo;s here: https://youtu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new GUI for building and managing clusters - PCluster Manager</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/a-new-gui-for-building-and-managing-clusters-pcluster-manager.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 15:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/a-new-gui-for-building-and-managing-clusters-pcluster-manager.html</guid>
      <description>Charlie Gruenweld, our newest Principal Engineer in the HPC org, took advantage of the new API in ParallelCluster and a few dozen years of web development revolutions to build a snappy UI for creating and managing clusters that makes it nearly impossible to go wrong - and gives you immediate access to some of ParallelCluster&amp;rsquo;s most powerful features.
In less than 20 minutes, you&amp;rsquo;ll grok how to create a cluster, run jobs, spawn elastic (disposable) nodes, and jump into a full graphical desktop to run visual applications on the cluster itself.
This is the project that brings it all together. I hope you enjoy this as much as I did.
If you have ideas for technical topics you&amp;rsquo;d like to see us cover in a future show, let us know by finding us on Twitter (@TechHpc) and DM&amp;rsquo;ing us with your idea.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
