<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quantum technologies on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</title>
    <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/quantum-technologies.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quantum technologies on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/quantum-technologies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simulating 44-Qubit quantum circuits using AWS ParallelCluster</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/simulating-44-qubit-quantum-circuits-using-aws-parallelcluster.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/simulating-44-qubit-quantum-circuits-using-aws-parallelcluster.html</guid>
      <description>A key part of the development of quantum hardware and quantum algorithms is simulation using existing classical architectures and HPC techniques. In this blog post, we describe how to perform large-scale quantum circuits simulations using AWS ParallelCluster with QuEST, the Quantum Exact Simulation Toolkit. We demonstrate a simple and rapid deployment of computational resources up to 4,096 compute instances to simulate random quantum circuits with up to 44 qubits. We were able to allocate as many as 4096 EC2 instances of c5.18xlarge to simulate a non-trivial 44 qubit quantum circuit in fewer than 3.5 hours.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Chemistry Calculation with FHI-aims code on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/quantum-chemistry-calculation-with-fhi-aims-code-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/quantum-chemistry-calculation-with-fhi-aims-code-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>This article was contributed by Dr. Fabio Baruffa, Sr. HPC and QC Solutions Architect at AWS, and Dr. Jesús Pérez Ríos, Group Leader at the Fritz Haber Institute, Max-Planck Society. Introduction Quantum chemistry – the study of the inherently quantum interactions between atoms forming part of molecules – is a cornerstone of modern chemistry. […]
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
