<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life-sciences on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</title>
    <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/life-sciences.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in life-sciences on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/life-sciences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Life Sciences on AWS HPC</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/life-sciences.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/life-sciences.html</guid>
      <description> Learn about Life Sciences on AWS HPC </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Genomics Pipelines Using Intel’s Open Omics Acceleration Framework on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/accelerating-genomics-pipelines-using-intels-open-omics-acceleration-framework-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/accelerating-genomics-pipelines-using-intels-open-omics-acceleration-framework-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>In this blog, we showcase the first version of Open Omics and benchmark three applications that are used in processing NGS data – sequence alignment tools BWA-MEM, minimap2, and single cell ATAC-Seq on Xeon-based Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) Instances.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Genomic Data using Amazon Genomics CLI and Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/analyzing-genomic-data-using-amazon-genomics-cli-and-amazon-sagemaker.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/analyzing-genomic-data-using-amazon-genomics-cli-and-amazon-sagemaker.html</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, we demonstrate how to leverage the AWS Genomics Command line and Amazon SageMaker to analyze large-scale exome sequences and derive meaningful insights. We use the bioinformatics workflow manager Nextflow, it’s open source library of pipelines, NF-Core, and AWS Batch.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Thermo Fisher Scientific Accelerated Cryo-EM using AWS ParallelCluster</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/how-thermo-fisher-scientific-accelerated-cryo-em-using-aws-parallelcluster.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/how-thermo-fisher-scientific-accelerated-cryo-em-using-aws-parallelcluster.html</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, we’ll walk you through the process of building a successful Cryo-EM benchmarking pilot using AWS ParallelCluster, Amazon FSx for Lustre, and cryoSPARC (from Structura Biotechnology) and explain some of our design decisions along the way.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with NVIDIA Clara Parabricks on AWS Batch using AWS CloudFormation</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/getting-started-with-nvidia-clara-parabricks-on-aws-batch-using-aws-cloudformation.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/getting-started-with-nvidia-clara-parabricks-on-aws-batch-using-aws-cloudformation.html</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, we’ll show how you can run NVIDIA Parabricks on AWS Batch leveraging AWS CloudFormation templates. Parabricks is a GPU-accelerated tool for secondary genomic analysis. It reduces the runtime of variant calling on a 30x human genome from 30 hours to just 30 minutes, and leverages AWS Batch to provide an interface that scales compute jobs across multiple instances in the cloud.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running cost-effective GROMACS simulations using Amazon EC2 Spot Instances with AWS ParallelCluster</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-cost-effective-gromacs-simulations-using-amazon-ec2-spot-instances-with-aws-parallelcluster.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-cost-effective-gromacs-simulations-using-amazon-ec2-spot-instances-with-aws-parallelcluster.html</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, we cover how to run GROMACS – a popular open source designed for simulations of proteins, lipids, and nucleic acids – cost effectively by leveraging EC2 Spot Instances within AWS ParallelCluster. We also show how to checkpoint GROMACS to recover gracefully from possible Spot Instance interruptions.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking NVIDIA Clara Parabricks Somatic Variant Calling Pipeline on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/benchmarking-nvidia-clara-parabricks-somatic-variant-calling-pipeline-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/benchmarking-nvidia-clara-parabricks-somatic-variant-calling-pipeline-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>Somatic variants are genetic alterations which are not inherited but acquired during one’s lifespan, for example those that are present in cancer tumors. In this post, we will demonstrate how to perform somatic variant calling from matched tumor and normal genome sequence data, as well as tumor-only whole genome and whole exome datasets using an NVIDIA GPU-accelerated Parabricks pipeline, and compare the results with baseline CPU-based workflows.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-based drug discovery with Atomwise and WEKA Data Platform</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/ai-based-drug-discovery-with-atomwise-and-weka-data-platform.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/ai-based-drug-discovery-with-atomwise-and-weka-data-platform.html</guid>
      <description>Drug discovery is an expensive proposition, with a $2.6 billion cost over 10 years and just a 12% success rate. AI promises to significantly improve the success rate by finding small molecule hits for undruggable targets. On the forefront of using AI in drug discovery is Atomwise, with its AtomNet® platform. In this blog, we will lay out the challenges of the drug discovery process, and show how AI/ML startups are solving these challenges using solutions from Atomwise, AWS, and WEKA.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science workflows at insitro: how redun uses the advanced service features from AWS Batch and AWS Glue</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/data-science-workflows-at-insitro-how-redun-uses-the-advanced-service-features-from-aws-batch-and-aws-glue.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/data-science-workflows-at-insitro-how-redun-uses-the-advanced-service-features-from-aws-batch-and-aws-glue.html</guid>
      <description>Matt Rasmussen, VP of Software Engineering at insitro, expands on his first post on redun, insitro’s data science tool for bioinformatics, to describe how redun makes use of advanced AWS features. Specifically, Matt describes how AWS Batch’s Array Jobs is used to support workflows with large fan-out, and how AWS Glue’s DynamicFrame is used to run computationally heterogenous workflows with different back-end needs such as Spark, all in the same workflow definition.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science workflows at insitro: using redun on AWS Batch</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/data-science-workflows-at-insitro-using-redun-on-aws-batch.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/data-science-workflows-at-insitro-using-redun-on-aws-batch.html</guid>
      <description>Matt Rasmussen, VP of Software Engineering at insitro describes their recently released, open-source data science framework, redun, which allows data scientists to define complex scientific workflows that scale from their laptop to large-scale distributed runs on serverless platforms like AWS Batch and AWS Glue. I this post, Matt shows how redun lends itself to Bioinformatics workflows which typically involve wrapping Unix-based programs that require file staging to and from object storage. In the next blog post, Matt describes how redun scales to large and heterogenous workflows by leveraging AWS Batch features such as Array Jobs and AWS Glue features such as Glue DynamicFrame.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a digital map of COVID-19 virus for discovery of new treatment compounds</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/creating-a-digital-map-of-covid-19-virus-for-discovery-of-new-treatment-compounds.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/creating-a-digital-map-of-covid-19-virus-for-discovery-of-new-treatment-compounds.html</guid>
      <description>Quantum physics and high-performance computing have slashed research times for a consortium of researchers led by Qubit Pharmaceuticals. This post describes the discovery of chemical substances that may lead to new COVID-19 treatments in only six months using cloud technology.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GROMACS performance on Amazon EC2 with Intel Ice Lake processors</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/gromacs-performance-on-amazon-ec2-with-intel-ice-lake-processors.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/gromacs-performance-on-amazon-ec2-with-intel-ice-lake-processors.html</guid>
      <description>We recently launched two new Amazon EC2 instance families based on Intel’s Ice Lake – the C6i and M6i. These instances provide higher core counts and take advantage of generational performance improvements on Intel’s Xeon scalable processor family architectures. In this post we show how GROMACS performs on these new instance families. We use similar methodologies as for previous posts where we characterized price-performance for CPU-only and GPU instances (Part 1, Part 2, Part 3), providing instance recommendations for different workload sizes.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating drug discovery with Amazon EC2 Spot Instances</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/accelerating-drug-discovery-with-amazon-ec2-spot-instances.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/accelerating-drug-discovery-with-amazon-ec2-spot-instances.html</guid>
      <description>We have been working with a team of researchers at the Max Planck Institute, helping them adopt the AWS cloud for drug research applications in the pharmaceutical industry. In this post, we’ll focus on how the team at Max Planck obtained thousands of EC2 Spot Instances spread across multiple AWS Regions for running their compute intensive simulations in a cost-effective manner, and how their solution will be enhanced further using the new Spot Placement Score API.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking the NVIDIA Clara Parabricks germline pipeline on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/benchmarking-the-nvidia-clara-parabricks-germline-pipeline-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/benchmarking-the-nvidia-clara-parabricks-germline-pipeline-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>This blog provides an overview of NVIDIA’s Clara Parabricks along with a guide on how to use Parabricks within the AWS Marketplace. It focuses on germline analysis for whole genome and whole exome applications using GPU accelerated bwa-mem and GATK’s HaplotypeCaller.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running a 3.2M vCPU HPC Workload on AWS with YellowDog</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-a-32m-vcpu-hpc-workload-on-aws-with-yellowdog.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-a-32m-vcpu-hpc-workload-on-aws-with-yellowdog.html</guid>
      <description>OMass Therapeutics, a biotechnology company identifying medicines against highly validated target ecosystems, used Yellowdog on AWS to analyze and screen 337 million compounds in 7 hours, a task which would have taken two months using an on-premises HPC cluster. YellowDog, based in Bristol in the UK, ran the drug discovery application on an extremely large, multi-region cluster in AWS with the AWS ‘pay-as-you-go’ pricing model. It provided a central, unified interface to monitor and manage AWS Region selection, compute provisioning, job allocation and execution. The entire workload completed in 65 minutes, enabling scientists to start work on analysis the same day, significantly accelerating the drug discovery process. In this post, we’ll discuss the AWS and YellowDog services we deployed, and the mechanisms used to scale to 3.2m vCPUs using multiple EC2 instance types across multiple regions in 33 minutes, running at a 95% utilization rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running 20k simulations in 3 days to accelerate early stage drug discovery with AWS Batch</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-20k-simulations-in-3-days-to-accelerate-early-stage-drug-discovery-with-aws-batch.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-20k-simulations-in-3-days-to-accelerate-early-stage-drug-discovery-with-aws-batch.html</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, we’ll describe an ensemble run of 20K simulations to accelerate the drug discovery process, while also optimizing for run time and cost. We used two popular open-source packages — GROMACS, which does a molecular dynamics simulations, and pmx, a free-energy calculation package from the Computational Biomolecular Dynamics Group at Max Planck Institute in Germany.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AWS Batch Console Support for Step Functions Workflows</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/using-aws-batch-console-support-for-step-functions-workflows.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/using-aws-batch-console-support-for-step-functions-workflows.html</guid>
      <description>Last year, we published the Genomics Secondary Analysis Using AWS Step Functions and AWS Batch solution as a companion solution to the Genomics Data Transfer, Analytics, and Machine Learning Using AWS Services whitepaper. Since then, many customers have used the secondary analysis solution to automate their bioinformatics pipelines in AWS. A common pain point expressed […]
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running GROMACS on GPU instances: multi-node price-performance</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-gromacs-on-gpu-instances-multi-node-price-performance.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-gromacs-on-gpu-instances-multi-node-price-performance.html</guid>
      <description>This three-part series of posts cover the price performance characteristics of running GROMACS on Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) GPU instances. Part 1 covered some background no GROMACS and how it utilizes GPUs for acceleration. Part 2 covered the price performance of GROMACS on a particular GPU instance family running on a single instance. […]
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running GROMACS on GPU instances: single-node price-performance</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-gromacs-on-gpu-instances-single-node-price-performance.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-gromacs-on-gpu-instances-single-node-price-performance.html</guid>
      <description>This three-part series of posts cover the price performance characteristics of running GROMACS on Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) GPU instances. Part 1 covered some background no GROMACS and how it utilizes GPUs for acceleration. This post (Part 2) covers the price performance of GROMACS on a particular GPU instance family running on a […]
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running GROMACS on GPU instances</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-gromacs-on-gpu-instances.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-gromacs-on-gpu-instances.html</guid>
      <description>Comparing the performance of real applications across different Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instance types is the best way we’ve found for finding optimal configurations for HPC applications here at AWS. Previously, we wrote about price-performance optimizations for GROMACS that showed how the GROMACS molecular dynamics simulation runs on single instances, and how it […]
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Screening of Novel Active Drug Compounds on AWS with Orion®</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/virtual-screening-of-novel-active-drug-compounds-on-aws-with-orion.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/virtual-screening-of-novel-active-drug-compounds-on-aws-with-orion.html</guid>
      <description>Computer-aided drug discovery (CADD) has been a key player in lowering the cost and speeding up the timeline for drug development. CADD uses high performance computing (HPC) resources to virtually screen databases with billions of molecules. It can speed up the searching of potential drug molecules, and filter out molecules and compounds that are unsuitable. OpenEye Scientific developed Orion®, a cloud-based molecular design platform for CADD. Orion provides computational chemists with virtually unlimited HPC resources. These include data visualization, collaboration, and workflow management tools that help them perform calculations more efficiently. In this post, we describe the Orion architecture on AWS, and it’s capabilities to address the challenges in drug development.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New: Introducing AWS ParallelCluster 3</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/new-introducing-aws-parallelcluster-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/new-introducing-aws-parallelcluster-3.html</guid>
      <description>Running HPC workloads, like computational fluid dynamics (CFD), molecular dynamics, or weather forecasting typically involves a lot of moving parts. You need a hundreds or thousands of compute cores, a job scheduler for keeping them fed, a shared file system that’s tuned for throughput or IOPS (or both), loads of libraries, a fast network, and […]
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stion – a Software as a Service for Cryo-EM data processing on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/stion-a-software-as-a-service-for-cryo-em-data-processing-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/stion-a-software-as-a-service-for-cryo-em-data-processing-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>This post was written by Swapnil Bhatkar, Cloud Engineer, NREL in collaboration with Edward Eng Ph.D. and Micah Rapp Ph.D, both SEMC/NYSBC, and Evan Bollig Ph.D. and Aniket Deshpande, both AWS. Introduction Cryo-electron microscopy (Cryo-EM) technology allows biomedical researchers to image frozen biological molecules, such as proteins, viruses and nucleic acids, and obtain structures of […]
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating research and development of new medical treatments with HPC on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/accelerating-research-and-development-of-new-medical-treatments-with-hpc-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/accelerating-research-and-development-of-new-medical-treatments-with-hpc-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>Today, more than 290,000 researchers in France are working to provide better support and care for patients through modern medical treatment. To fulfill their mission, these researchers must be equipped with powerful tools. At AWS, we believe that technology has a critical role to play in medical research. Why? Because technology can take advantage of the significant amount of data generated in the healthcare system and in the research community to enable opportunities for more accurate diagnoses, and better treatments for many existing and future diseases. To support elite research in France, we are proud to be a sponsor of two French organizations: Gustave Roussy and Sorbonne University. AWS is providing them with the computing power and machine learning technologies needed to accelerate cancer research and develop a treatment for COVID-19.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GROMACS price-performance optimizations on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/gromacs-price-performance-optimizations-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/gromacs-price-performance-optimizations-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>Molecular dynamics (MD) is a simulation method for analyzing the movement and tracing trajectories of atoms and molecules where the dynamics of a system evolve over time. MD simulations are used across various domains such as material sciences, biochemistry, biophysics and are typically used in two broad ways to study a system. The importance of […]
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
