<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>performance on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</title>
    <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/performance.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in performance on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 16:35:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/performance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What makes the AWS Graviton 3 so interesting to HPC and AI/ML customers?</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/what-makes-the-aws-graviton-3-so-interesting-to-hpc-and-aiml-customers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 16:35:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/what-makes-the-aws-graviton-3-so-interesting-to-hpc-and-aiml-customers.html</guid>
      <description>The AWS Graviton 3 will be launched this year as part of the new C7g instance. Inside this chip are some interesting innovations that already have a lot of HPC and AI/ML customers interested.
We sat down with Olly Perks, who recently joined AWS HPC Engineering from Arm, to discuss what&amp;rsquo;s most interesting. This is the first of a series of Tech Shorts covering the Graviton 3 architecture. We&amp;rsquo;ll deep dive on techniques and tools for getting the most out of these CPUs.
If you have ideas for technical topics you&amp;rsquo;d like to see us cover in a future show, let us know by finding us on Twitter (@TechHpc) and DM&amp;rsquo;ing us with your idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arm/AWS Cloud Hackathon - Performance Portability with Tom Deakin</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/armaws-cloud-hackathon-performance-portability-with-tom-deakin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 15:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/armaws-cloud-hackathon-performance-portability-with-tom-deakin.html</guid>
      <description>This is a talk that was delivered at the AWS/Arm Cloud Hackathon in July 2021.
Tom Deakin is a computer scientist at the University of Bristol, and speaks to us about how to build for portability, and what that really means in an era of so many hardware technology choices.
The Summer Hackathon ran for a week from July 12-16 in 2021. It&amp;rsquo;s purpose was to assemble the HPC community around a common goal of beginning the porting/testing/tuning process for dozens of codes to use Arm-based processors, in this case, AWS&amp;rsquo;s Graviton2&amp;rsquo;s.
During the week we had a series of talks from global leaders and experts in various fields from compilers to networking, profiling debugging and tooling. We&amp;rsquo;ve published all the talks here in the HPC Tech Shorts channel, in the hope that everyone gets some value from them.
If you want to join in our collective effort to boost the performance of HPC workloads on Arm, DM us at Twitter (@TechHpc) or head to a-hug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WRF performance teardown on Graviton vs x86</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/wrf-performance-teardown-on-graviton-vs-x86.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 16:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/wrf-performance-teardown-on-graviton-vs-x86.html</guid>
      <description>(A complete teardown of WRF performance on x86 and AWS Graviton, from memory subsystems, compilers and MPI stacks).
Weather simulation is a reliably difficult workload for almost any HPC architecture and is often used as a litmus test by many customers before they look too hard at a novel or different systems. Customers have asked us frequently about our performance for codes like WRF, and that’s been even more the case since we launched our Arm-based processor, the AWS Graviton2, in a range of EC2 instances.
So it’s exciting that Karthik Raman and Matt Koop (two leading engineers from our global HPC solution architecture team) dived deep to look at WRF’s performance across a range of instance types (both Intel and Graviton), with EFA (our fast fabric, as you might remember from last week) as well as investigating the impact of different MPIs and compilers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
