<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FSx for OpenZFS on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</title>
    <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/fsx-for-openzfs.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in FSx for OpenZFS on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/fsx-for-openzfs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Expanded filesystems support in AWS ParallelCluster 3.2</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/expanded-filesystems-support-in-aws-parallelcluster-32.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/expanded-filesystems-support-in-aws-parallelcluster-32.html</guid>
      <description>AWS ParallelCluster version 3.2 introduces support for two new Amazon FSx filesystem types (NetApp ONTAP and OpenZFS). It also lifts the limit on the number of filesystem mounts you can have on your cluster. We’ll show you how, and help you with the details for getting this going right away.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenZFS created quickly with checkpoints, backups and big performance</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/openzfs-created-quickly-with-checkpoints-backups-and-big-performance.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 15:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/openzfs-created-quickly-with-checkpoints-backups-and-big-performance.html</guid>
      <description>We launched Amazon FSx for OpenZFS at re:invent in December, and well let&amp;rsquo;s just say it&amp;rsquo;s been more than a bit popular :-)
ZFS and it&amp;rsquo;s friends have been a long time favorite of the HPC community, so we asked Delwin Olivan, the Snr Product Manager for the service to come and show us how easy it is to get big scale, and big performance with very little effort.
Auto-backups and one-click snapshots are exactly as they&amp;rsquo;re described on the lid. Which is awesome.
If you have ideas for technical topics you&amp;rsquo;d like to see us cover in a future show, let us know by finding us on Twitter (@TechHpc) and DM&amp;rsquo;ing us with your idea.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
