<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>genomics on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</title>
    <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/genomics.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in genomics on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 11:29:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/genomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Genomics workflow set made easy with AWS Genomics CLI</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/genomics-workflow-set-made-easy-with-aws-genomics-cli.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 11:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/genomics-workflow-set-made-easy-with-aws-genomics-cli.html</guid>
      <description>The AWS Genomics CLI (or AGC) seriously removes all the grunt work involved in setting up bioinformatics pipelines to run in the cloud. We know that Snakemake, Cromwell, NextFlow and miniWDL all work happily in the cloud on AWS Batch, but AGC means you don&amp;rsquo;t have to know to set all that stuff up - it does it for you.
You can have completely separate tool chains using completely different workflow languages all running at the same time, on the same infrastructure (if you like), sharing data and tooling.
Lee Pang from the dev team that built this came along to show us how it works, and - most importantly - how easy it is to get productive. Zero to hero in less than 30 mins - it&amp;rsquo;s really impressive.
If you have ideas for technical topics you&amp;rsquo;d like to see us cover in a future show, let us know by finding us on Twitter (@TechHpc) and DM&amp;rsquo;ing us with your idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>miniWDL workflows with 100% cloud elasticity, and no DevOps geekery</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/miniwdl-workflows-with-100-cloud-elasticity-and-no-devops-geekery.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 16:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/miniwdl-workflows-with-100-cloud-elasticity-and-no-devops-geekery.html</guid>
      <description>Mike Lin is the creator and maintainer of miniWDL and has been working with our Genomics and ML teams to integrate it with Sagemaker Studio and AWS Batch. The result is a working environment that&amp;rsquo;s completely familiar and easy to use (it&amp;rsquo;s Jupyter, after all) and yet has access to all the elasticity of the cloud, but without ever needing to leave the familiar notebook interface to make that magic happen.
It&amp;rsquo;s a really cool example of bringing the tools to science, rather than forcing the scientists to understand yet another new tool.
If you have ideas for technical topics you&amp;rsquo;d like to see us cover in a future show, let us know by finding us on Twitter (@TechHpc) and DM&amp;rsquo;ing us with your idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with bioinformatics on AWS with Swaine Chen from GIS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/getting-started-with-bioinformatics-on-aws-with-swaine-chen-from-gis.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 13:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/getting-started-with-bioinformatics-on-aws-with-swaine-chen-from-gis.html</guid>
      <description>Swaine Chen had a problem: his new group at the Genomics Institute of Singapore needed common tooling involving zillions of utilities, scripts carrying algorithms and techniques, so they could migrate their workloads from their on-premises infrastructure and over to the cloud.
His solution was to build a golden AMI. So much better is that he automated the production of the AMI, and documented it in GitHub, for the world to see, and for the world to use.
Today&amp;rsquo;s discussion shows just a glimpse of what his team has built, and you can get all the goodness in the hands-on training workshops he&amp;rsquo;s offering (for free) to anyone in the world who wants to sign up.
If you want to know more about the workshops, or sign up, go here: https://hpc.news/giswsregister
If you want to plunder all this goodness and use it for the forces of good (not evil!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nextflow Tower  and how it makes it easy to manage a lot of infrastructure quickly.</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/nextflow-tower-and-how-it-makes-it-easy-to-manage-a-lot-of-infrastructure-quickly.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 15:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/nextflow-tower-and-how-it-makes-it-easy-to-manage-a-lot-of-infrastructure-quickly.html</guid>
      <description>Nextflow Tower became necessary when lots of Nextflow users started to leave the confines of their existing environments in search of more compute, more storage, more capabilities. Nextflow made their workflows portable, but there was still a lot of relatively complex work to be done standing up cloud infrastructure, setting limits, choosing instances, pondering VPCs, Batch compute environments &amp;hellip; You get the idea.
Nextflow Tower massively simplifies that. It integrates deeply with all these environments (lots of clouds, lots of cluster types, and even in hybrid mode) such that a researcher with a good idea can go from laptop to server to cluster to massive compute farm, step-by-step as their idea and ambition grows.
Evan Floden, the CEO of Seqera Labs and a core developer of Nextflow (along with his friend and business partner Paolo Di Tommaso) steps in to take us for a drive of Tower and explains some of the tech underpinning it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NF Core is an example to all compute-intensive scientific fields. They should all watch this.</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/nf-core-is-an-example-to-all-compute-intensive-scientific-fields-they-should-all-watch-this.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 20:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/nf-core-is-an-example-to-all-compute-intensive-scientific-fields-they-should-all-watch-this.html</guid>
      <description>NF Core is an open source repository of Nextflow workflows that can be downloaded, shared, forked, updated, tested and validated. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard that quote from Isaac Newtown about seeing further by standing on the shoulders of giants: well this is the ladder modern day scientists are using to climb up those very big shoulders. Phil Ewels from the SciLife lab at Stockholm University walks us through some of the history of NF Core and gives us a demo of how easy it is to use, and the cool tools he and his project team have built around to just make it &amp;hellip; a no brainer. Every domain of science should be looking at how this works, because every field of science performs a workflow on data - and those workflows are getting increasingly complicated. If you have ideas for technical topics you&amp;rsquo;d like to see us cover in a future show, let us know by finding us on Twitter (@TechHpc) and DM&amp;rsquo;ing us with your idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nextflow has changed the way science does computing and energized a community. We need this.</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/nextflow-has-changed-the-way-science-does-computing-and-energized-a-community-we-need-this.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 17:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/nextflow-has-changed-the-way-science-does-computing-and-energized-a-community-we-need-this.html</guid>
      <description>In recent years, we’ve all been amazed at how large areas of scientific computing have moved to abstract their workflows away from the details of systems and cluster architecture. Bioinformatics has really lead the way in this regard - exploiting the fact that they came to large scale computing without decades of legacy code.
Nextflow is an open source project that has been hugely impactful in that movement, enabling a community leverage each other&amp;rsquo;s scientific work and - honestly - stand on each others&amp;rsquo; shoulders to reach further. We didn&amp;rsquo;t need a pandemic to drive that point home, but they played their part there too (more on that in a later show).
Today we’re joined by Evan Floden, who is a principle author of Nextflow (along with other leaders like Paolo Di Tommaso who was one of Nextflow’s creators). Evan is also the CEO of Seqera Labs, the company he and Paolo formed to provide extra support to Nextflow users, and to take management of the workflows and integration with the underlying infrastructure to a whole new level.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
