<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Best Practices on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</title>
    <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/best-practices.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Best Practices on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/best-practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting the Best Price Performance for Numerical Weather Prediction Workloads on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/getting-the-best-price-performance-for-numerical-weather-prediction-workloads-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/getting-the-best-price-performance-for-numerical-weather-prediction-workloads-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>In this post, we will provide an overview of Numerical Weather Prediction (NWP) workloads, and the AWS HPC-optimized services for it. We’ll test three popular NWP codes: WRF, MPAS, and FV3GFS.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Genomics Pipelines Using Intel’s Open Omics Acceleration Framework on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/accelerating-genomics-pipelines-using-intels-open-omics-acceleration-framework-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/accelerating-genomics-pipelines-using-intels-open-omics-acceleration-framework-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>In this blog, we showcase the first version of Open Omics and benchmark three applications that are used in processing NGS data – sequence alignment tools BWA-MEM, minimap2, and single cell ATAC-Seq on Xeon-based Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) Instances.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Scalable Predictive Modeling Framework in AWS – Part 3</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/building-a-scalable-predictive-modeling-framework-in-aws-part-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/building-a-scalable-predictive-modeling-framework-in-aws-part-3.html</guid>
      <description>In this final part of this three-part blog series on building predictive models at scale in AWS, we will use the synthetic dataset and the models generated in the previous post to showcase the model updating and sensitivity analysis capabilities of the aws-do-pm framework.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Scalable Predictive Modeling Framework in AWS – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/building-a-scalable-predictive-modeling-framework-in-aws-part-2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/building-a-scalable-predictive-modeling-framework-in-aws-part-2.html</guid>
      <description>In the first part of this three-part blog series, we introduced the aws-do-pm framework for building predictive models at scale in AWS. In this blog, we showcase a sample application for predicting the life of batteries in a fleet of electric vehicles, using the aws-do-pm framework.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Scalable Predictive Modeling Framework in AWS – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/building-a-scalable-predictive-modeling-framework-in-aws-part-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/building-a-scalable-predictive-modeling-framework-in-aws-part-1.html</guid>
      <description>Predictive models have powered the design and analysis of real-world systems such as jet engines, automobiles, and powerplants for decades. These models are used to provide insights on system performance and to run simulations, at a fraction of the cost compared to experiments with physical hardware. In this first post of three, we described the motivation and general architecture of the open-source aws-do-pm framework project for building predictive models at scale in AWS.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the AWS Batch termination process</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/understanding-the-aws-batch-termination-process.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/understanding-the-aws-batch-termination-process.html</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, we help you understand the AWS Batch job termination process and how you may take actions to gracefully terminate a job by capturing SIGTERM signal inside the application. It provides you with an efficient way to exit your Batch jobs. You also get to know about how job timeouts occur, and how the retry operation works with both traditional AWS Batch jobs and array jobs.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encoding workflow dependencies in AWS Batch</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/encoding-workflow-dependencies-in-aws-batch.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/encoding-workflow-dependencies-in-aws-batch.html</guid>
      <description>This post covers the different ways you can encode a dependency between basic and array jobs in AWS Batch. We also cover why you may want to encode dependencies outside of Batch altogether using a workflow system like AWS Step Functions or Apache Airflow.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting the best OpenFOAM Performance on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/getting-the-best-openfoam-performance-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/getting-the-best-openfoam-performance-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>OpenFOAM is one the most widely used Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) packages and helps companies in a broad range of sectors (automotive, aerospace, energy, and life-sciences) to conduct research and design new products. In this post, we’ll discuss six practical things you can do as an OpenFOAM user to run your simulations faster and more cost effectively.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling a read-intensive, low-latency file system to 10M&#43; IOPs</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/scaling-a-read-intensive-low-latency-file-system-to-10m-iops.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/scaling-a-read-intensive-low-latency-file-system-to-10m-iops.html</guid>
      <description>Many shared file systems are used in supporting read-intensive applications, like financial backtesting. These applications typically exploit copies of datasets whose authoritative copy resides somewhere else. For small datasets, in-memory databases and caching techniques can yield impressive results. However, low latency flash-based scalable shared file systems can provide both massive IOPs and bandwidth. They’re also easy to adopt because of their use of a file-level abstraction. In this post, I’ll share how to easily create and scale a shared, distributed POSIX compatible file system that performs at local NVMe speeds for files opened read-only.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting bitrates into perspective</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/putting-bitrates-into-perspective.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/putting-bitrates-into-perspective.html</guid>
      <description>Recently, we talked about the advances NICE DCV has made to push pixels from cloud-hosted desktops or applications over the internet even more efficiently than before. Since we published that post on this blog channel, we’ve been asked by several customers whether all this efficient pixel-pushing could lead to outbound data charges moving up on their AWS bill. We decided to try it on your behalf, and share the details with you in this post. The bottom line? The charges are unlikely to be significant unless you’re doing intensive streaming (such as gaming) and other cost optimizations (like AWS Instance Savings Plans) that will have more impact on your bill.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running GROMACS on GPU instances: multi-node price-performance</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-gromacs-on-gpu-instances-multi-node-price-performance.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-gromacs-on-gpu-instances-multi-node-price-performance.html</guid>
      <description>This three-part series of posts cover the price performance characteristics of running GROMACS on Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) GPU instances. Part 1 covered some background no GROMACS and how it utilizes GPUs for acceleration. Part 2 covered the price performance of GROMACS on a particular GPU instance family running on a single instance. […]
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running GROMACS on GPU instances: single-node price-performance</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-gromacs-on-gpu-instances-single-node-price-performance.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-gromacs-on-gpu-instances-single-node-price-performance.html</guid>
      <description>This three-part series of posts cover the price performance characteristics of running GROMACS on Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) GPU instances. Part 1 covered some background no GROMACS and how it utilizes GPUs for acceleration. This post (Part 2) covers the price performance of GROMACS on a particular GPU instance family running on a […]
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running GROMACS on GPU instances</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-gromacs-on-gpu-instances.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-gromacs-on-gpu-instances.html</guid>
      <description>Comparing the performance of real applications across different Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instance types is the best way we’ve found for finding optimal configurations for HPC applications here at AWS. Previously, we wrote about price-performance optimizations for GROMACS that showed how the GROMACS molecular dynamics simulation runs on single instances, and how it […]
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Batch Dos and Don’ts: Best Practices in a Nutshell</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/aws-batch-dos-and-donts-best-practices-in-a-nutshell.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/aws-batch-dos-and-donts-best-practices-in-a-nutshell.html</guid>
      <description>AWS Batch is a service that enables scientists and engineers to run computational workloads at virtually any scale without requiring them to manage a complex architecture. In this blog post, we share a set of best practices and practical guidance devised from our experience working with customers in running and optimizing their computational workloads. The readers will learn how to optimize their costs with Amazon EC2 Spot on AWS Batch, how to troubleshoot their architecture should an issue arise and how to tune their architecture and containers layout to run at scale.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bare metal performance with the AWS Nitro System</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/bare-metal-performance-with-the-aws-nitro-system.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/bare-metal-performance-with-the-aws-nitro-system.html</guid>
      <description>High Performance Computing (HPC) is known as a domain where applications are well-optimized to get the highest performance possible on a platform. Unsurprisingly, a common question when moving a workload to AWS is what performance difference there may be from an existing on-premises “bare metal” platform. This blog will show the performance differential between “bare metal” instances and instances that use the AWS Nitro hypervisor is negligible for the evaluated HPC workloads.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical weather prediction on AWS Graviton2</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/numerical-weather-prediction-on-aws-graviton2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/numerical-weather-prediction-on-aws-graviton2.html</guid>
      <description>The Weather Research and Forecasting (WRF) model is a numerical weather prediction (NWP) system designed to serve both atmospheric research and operational forecasting needs. With the release of Arm-based AWS Graviton2 Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2) instances, a common question has been how these instances perform on large-scale NWP workloads. In this blog, we will present results from a standard WRF benchmark simulation and compare across three different instance types.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reader Question: What is the difference between canceling and terminating a job in AWS Batch?</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/reader-question-what-is-the-difference-between-canceling-and-terminating-a-job-in-aws-batch.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/reader-question-what-is-the-difference-between-canceling-and-terminating-a-job-in-aws-batch.html</guid>
      <description>A customer asked us what is the difference between the CancelJob and TerminateJob API calls in AWS Batch. This post provides an overview of AWS Batch job states, and how these two API calls effect the job requests that you have submitted.
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GROMACS price-performance optimizations on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/gromacs-price-performance-optimizations-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/gromacs-price-performance-optimizations-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>Molecular dynamics (MD) is a simulation method for analyzing the movement and tracing trajectories of atoms and molecules where the dynamics of a system evolve over time. MD simulations are used across various domains such as material sciences, biochemistry, biophysics and are typically used in two broad ways to study a system. The importance of […]
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running finite element analysis using Simcenter Nastran on AWS</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-finite-element-analysis-using-simcenter-nastran-on-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/running-finite-element-analysis-using-simcenter-nastran-on-aws.html</guid>
      <description>This post was written by Dnyanesh Digraskar, Sr. Partner Solutions Architect for HPC at AWS and co-authored by Wei Zhang and Ravi Gupta, Sr Software Engineers for Simcenter Nastran at Siemens. Introduction In this blog, we demonstrate the deployment, performance, and price comparisons of Simcenter Nastran for three finite element analysis (FEA) based use cases […]
Read the full post at the AWS HPC Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
