<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>networking on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</title>
    <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/networking.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in networking on Day 1 HPC (Staging)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AWS Elastic Fabric Adapter</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/efa.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/efa.html</guid>
      <description>Elastic Fabric Adapter (EFA) The AWS Elastic Fabric Adapter (EFA) is a high-performance networking interface for Amazon EC2 instances that enables you to run applications requiring high levels of inter-node communications at scale on AWS.
It&amp;rsquo;s natively supported by Intel MPI, Open MPI, MVAPICH, and NCCL and is available on across CPU and GPU architectures including our own AWS Graviton processors.
How does it work? Amazon EC2 compute infrastructure is very much not like a ‘normal’ supercomputer (whatever that is). We don’t start with a blank page every few years and design the next big system. It’s a little more like a city where we build on what’s there already, renovate occasionally, and push for bigger and better and faster, while keeping the lights on and the traffic flowing at all times.
While this leads to different design decisions, it also leads to interesting discoveries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of network conditions on application performance is complicated.</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/the-impact-of-network-conditions-on-application-performance-is-complicated.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 15:16:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/the-impact-of-network-conditions-on-application-performance-is-complicated.html</guid>
      <description>In the search for HPC application performance, there’s more than one way to build a network.
HPC applications (or “codes” as we usually call them) are often at the mercy of the network underpinning an HPC cluster. If your CPUs aren’t busy, it’s usually because something that’s meant to be feeding them data isn’t doing so at a fast enough rate. And often the culprit is the network.
Peter Mendygral has a lot of years of experience looking at networks and is one of the co-authors of the GPCnet benchmark, which aims to have a more nuanced look at how networks deliver for (or fail) the clusters built on them. In todays’s discussion, Pete speaks about the real world conditions found on many network fabrics, and shows us that when they depart from the idealized scenarios that common micro benchmarks measure, the results are anything but stellar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How EFA works and why we don&#39;t use infiniband in the cloud.</title>
      <link>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/how-efa-works-and-why-we-dont-use-infiniband-in-the-cloud.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 15:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://d175uvn6dnkepf.cloudfront.net/post/how-efa-works-and-why-we-dont-use-infiniband-in-the-cloud.html</guid>
      <description>AWS’s compute infrastructure is very much not like a ‘normal’ supercomputer (whatever that is). We don’t start with a blank page every few years and design the next big system. It’s more like a city where we have to build on what’s there already, renovate occasionally, and push for bigger and better and faster whilst keeping the lights on at all times.
That leads to a bunch of design decisions that drive our engineers in a very different direction and our Elastic Fabric Adapter is an example of just that. Brian Barrett (one of our Principal Engineers in the HPC team) joins us this week to talk about the genesis of EFA, how it works, and why it convinced us that we could do without specialist fabrics like Infiniband and still deliver the same (or better) application scaling performance that our HPC customers were pushing us for.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
